Inventory of the Frederick E. Fuhrman photographs
Hoover Institution Archives
Frederick E. Fuhrman photographs
1918-1919
87029
Hoover Institution Archives
6 envelopes (0.6 linear feet)
Depicts scenes along the Trans-Siberian Railroad and Chinese Eastern Railway in Siberia and Manchuria during the Russian Civil War, including troops and civilians of various nationalities, and railroad stock.
Fuhrman, Frederick E., 1880-1938.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1987.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
American engineer; officer, Russian Railway Service Corps, 1918-1919.
Scope and Content of Collection
Depicts scenes along the Trans-Siberian Railroad and Chinese Eastern Railway in Siberia and Manchuria during the Russian Civil War, including troops and civilians of various nationalities, and railroad stock. There are handwritten captions on the back of almost every photograph providing more thorough descriptions of each scene.
Chinese Eastern Railway--Pictorial works.; United States. Advisory Commission of Railway Experts to Russia--Pictorial works.; Velikaia Sibirskaia magistral'--Pictorial works.; Engineers.; Manchuria (China)--Pictorial works.; Railroads--China--Pictorial works.; Railroads--Soviet Union--Pictorial works.; Siberia (Russia)--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Pictorial works.; Soviet Union--History--Allied intervention, 1918-1920--Pictorial works.
- Photographs
  - Photographs, 1918-1919 (Envelope A)
    - Photographs of Booheedoo
      Scope and Content of Photographs
      These photographs of Booheedoo depict barracks, soldiers, railways, mountains, and other scenes.
    - Photographs of Hailar
      These photographs of Hailar depict railways, street scenes, and cemeteries. There are also many people pictured and captioned in these photographs.
    - Photographs of Harbin
      These photographs of Harbin are labeled as ones of Russian soldiers/cavalry, Chinese civilians and soldiers, as well as scenes of the cholera epidemic.
    - Photographs of Manchuria
      These photographs of Manchuria (explicit locations within the region are unspecified in these pictures) depict many scenes of refugees.
    - Photographs of Vladivostok
      These photographs of Vladivostok (Russia) depict soldiers and overall scenery.
    - Photographs of Unknown Locations
      These are photographs taken in locations that are unidentified by their captions. They mainly depict soldiers and other scenes.
  - Photographs, 1918-1919 (Envelope B)
    Scope and Contents
    This folder contains photographs concerning Manchuria (mainly Harbin and Hailar). Each photograph has a description.
    - Photographs of Booheedoo
      These photographs of Booheedoo depict various scenes, including trains and railways used by both civilians and soldiers.
    - Photographs of Hailar
      These photographs of Hailar depict railway scenes and people.
    - Photographs of Harbin
      These are photographs of Harbin specifcally capturing the notorious cholera epidemic, as well as civilians and soldiers.
    - Photographs of Manchuria
      These photographs depict scenes within Manchuria (explicit locations within the region are unidentified; many of the descriptions reference refugees.
    - Photographs of Unknown Locations
      This folder contains photographs taken at unidentified locations. There are quite a few photographs with captions describing scenes of Korean civilians, bridges, and railway cars.
  - Photographs, 1918-1919 (Envelope C)
    - Photographs of Hailar
      These photographs of Hailar depict scenes of homes and civilians.
    - Photographs of Harbin
      These are photographs of Harbin detailing scenes of the cholera epidemic, barracks, train station, and soldiers.
    - Photographs of Irkutsk
      These photographs of Irkutsk, Russia depict scenes of the jail, church, bridges, and civilians.
    - Photographs of Vladivostok
      These are some post cards with photographs of the 27th Infantry, first American troops in Siberia Vladivostok (Russia) in August 1918.
  - Photographs, 1918-1919 (Folder D, Envelope D)
    - Photographs of Booheedoo
      These are photographs of Booheedoo; they depict scenes of mountains and surrounding scenery, as well as the Red Cross hospital.
    - Photographs of Manchuria
      These photographs depict scenes of Manchuria (though specific areas within the region are unidentified), to include scenes of camels, refugees and other civilians, and actors/actresses taking part in some street festivities.
  - Photographs, 1918-1919 (Envelope E)
    - Photographs of Booheedoo
      These photographs of Booheedoo depict scenes of military/civilian trains and platforms, as well as civilians.
    - Photographs of Hailar
      These photographs of Hailar depict scenes of railway stations, storefronts, and Chinese civilians.
    - Photographs of Harbin
      These photographs of Harbin depict scenes of the cholera epidemic, soldiers, and civilians.
    - Photographs of Vladivostok
      These photographs of Vladivostok (Russia) depict scenes of railways, train depot, street cars, the fire department, and the surrounding natural scenery.
  - Photographs, 1918-1919 (Envelope F)
    - Photographs of Booheedoo
      These photographs of Booheedoo depict scenes that include images of soldiers and camels.
    - Photographs of Hailar
      These photographs of Hailar depict scenes of the Chinese temple, civilians, camels, and the overall scenery.
    - Photographs of Harbin
      These photographs of Harbin depict a diverse set of scenes concerning the cholera epidemic, train stations, boats, barracks, and soldiers.
      - Photographs of Futajen
        These photographs of Futajen (an area within Harbin) depict scenes of the cholera epidemic, nurses, and general street view.
    - Photographs of Honolulu
      These are photographs taken in Honolulu, which depict various scenes of soldiers, civilians, and overall scenery.
    - Photographs of Manchuria
      These photographs of Manchuria (though specific regions within are unidentified) depict various scenes including refugees, camels, and train depots.
    - Photographs of Vladivostok
      These photographs of Vladivostok (Russia) depict scenes of a cemetary, restaurants, and barracks.
    - Photographs of Unknown Locations
      These photographs were taken in unidentified locations (presumably within either China or Russia); they depict soldiers and civilians alike, as well as overall scenery. Some soldiers are specifically identified by name in the handwritten captions that can be found on the backs of many of the photos.